Weston Rose

1781 Spyglass Dr. #242, Austin, TX, 78746 | (979) 777-9021 | weston.rose86@gmail.com

GitHub: https://www.github.com/wrose001

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/weston-rose-b1259399/

Portfolio: https://wrose001.github.io/Personal-Website-1/

SUMMARY

Skilled web development specialist with six years of experience working in content management systems like Drupal and WordPress. Adaptable, collaborative, and self-directed problem-solver. Ten years of experience in higher education communications and administration. Currently serve as Program & Communications Coordinator at The University of Texas System Administration for the last four years. Life-long learner and former educator. Proficient in Google Analytics, SEO (Yoast), survey creation in SurveyMonkey, as well as the Adobe Creative Suite, Microsoft 365, and SharePoint.

TECHNICAL SKILLS & PROJECTS

Languages & Frameworks

MERN stack, Python, HTML 5, JavaScript, CSS, jQuery, MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, Heroku, GitHub, User Authentication, Testing, Reactstrap, Bootstrap, Bulma, markdown

Projects

- Shades Affordable Designer Sunglasses: Shades is an e-commerce MERN stack application built with authentication provided through OAuth. Functional and class components are utilized to allow users to leave customer reviews including a starrating (i.e., 3 out of 5 stars). Once logged in, users can add items to their cart, increase the quantity of a certain product, and watch as the total price, including tax is calculated. Materials.ui is used in lieu of PayPal to allow users to checkout, given that this is a prototype website. This application was the final project for my full-stack web development coding bootcamp. I served as a front-end developer and project manager for my team.
 - o **GitHub:** https://github.com/wrose001/shades.git
 - o **Link:** https://shades-ecommerce-westonrose.herokuapp.com
- Weston Rose's Company Directory: An employee directory built with React and a
 mock JSON data generated via https://mocokaroo.com. This app allows users to view
 non-sensitive data for all employees in a given company. Users can sort by first and
 last names in alphabetical and reverse-alphabetical order. Users can filter the list of
 employees by last name.
 - o **GitHub:** https://github.com/wrose001/employee-directory.git
 - Link: https://wrose001.github.io/employee-directory
- **Budget Tracker:** This budget tracker app allows users to add expenses and deposits either online or offline. Transactions that occur offline are populated when the app is brought back online. A standalone manifest allows users to save to their smartphone home screen as an app.
 - o **GitHub:** https://github.com/wrose001/Budget-Tracker.git
 - Link: https://budget-tracker-wr.herokuapp.com/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Program & Communications Coordinator
The University of Texas System Administration

Jun. 2016 – Present Austin, TX

- Recognized by director of web services for drafting and uploading SEO meta-descriptions for www.elevatetxed.utsystem.edu using Yoast plugin.
- Interpreted Google Analytics data requested by supervisor and automated a weekly Google Analytics report.
- Built and maintained web content for work-related websites and web sections in WordPress and Drupal.
- Created, distributed, and synthesized survey results using SurveyMonkey. Summarized
 results by creating tables and charts for the UT System Affordable Learning Accelerator
 Task Force, a 30+ group of higher education professionals working to make college more
 affordable to students by lowering the cost of high-quality textbooks and course materials.
- Drafted script for promotional video for <u>www.elevatetxed.utsystem.edu</u>.
- Organized a two-day, design-thinking, professional development workshop for 90+ academic advisors via Zoom, including polling, pre-assigned breakout rooms, and utilizing Mural for real-time virtual brainstorming.

Media & Communications Specialist Graduate Studies - Sam Houston State University Aug. 2013 – Jan. 2016 Huntsville, TX

- Built and maintained web content for the Office of Graduate Studies using WebCMS.
- Edited, wrote articles for, designed layout of, and published (in print and digitally) a yearly university research publication, "Distinguished Review: The Graduate Studies Magazine".
 Taught myself to use Adobe InDesign to produce the magazine.
- Increased participation by 5 times that of the previous year for the Graduate Research Exchange, while also coordinating two other awards programs, Outstanding Teaching Assistants and Thesis, Dissertation, and Capstone Project Awards.
- Recognized by supervisor and the Director of the Newton Gresham Library at SHSU for helping to develop a thesis/dissertation template using Visual Basic in Microsoft Word. Trained dozens of graduate student cohorts on how to use the template, how to write and format a thesis/dissertation, and how to manage the IRB process and meet library deadlines.
- Led the development of a university-wide thesis/dissertation electronic approval form using Perfect Forms.

Lecturer & Academic Advisor Sam Houston State University Aug. 2010 – Aug. 2013 Huntsville, TX

- Taught Rhetoric & Composition courses to freshmen colleges students, developed all teaching materials, and graded approximately 100 students' essays, tests, quizzes, and homework each semester.
- Advised undergraduate students across disciplines, assisted transfer students with course substitution, and connected students to services such as the Testing Center for CLEP options to reduce the cost of attendance and meet their educational and personal goals.

EDUCATION

Coding Bootcamp Certificate Program: Full-Stack
The University of Texas at Austin Coding BootcampDec. 2019 – May 2020
Austin, TXMaster of Arts in English Language & Literature
Sam Houston State UniversityJan. 2008 – Aug. 2010
Huntsville, TXBachelor of Arts in English Language & Literature
Sam Houston State UniversityAug. 2005 – Dec. 2007
Huntsville, TX

Other Certificates

- Certificate of Completion: Visual Design (Dec. 2019) from General Assembly. A twomonth course in UX/UI design covering communication design topics including layout, color theory, typography, Gestalt principles, user experience, and responsive design. Gained hands-on experience in Adobe XD.
- Strategic Communication Certificate (Aug. 2019) from UT Austin's Center for Professional Development. A five-class certificate program covering the following topics: Crisis Communications, Data Science, Storytelling, Audience-Driven Narratives, and Interacting with the Media.
- Certificate of Leader Development (Aug. 2018) from UT System Administration. Attended an internal summer-long leadership development program at my organization that included modules in management style, public speaking, and project management.